<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Reading | Sezina]]></title>
  <link href="http://sezina.github.com/blog/categories/reading/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sezina.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-08T17:11:22+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://sezina.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sezina]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[《整理的艺术》摘录]]></title>
    <link href="http://sezina.github.com/blog/2014/03/08/the-art-of-clean-up/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-08T17:06:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sezina.github.com/blog/2014/03/08/the-art-of-clean-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这个摘录挺郁闷的，基本就是每节的标题了。</p>

<h2>资料整理术——集中数据，分散浏览场所</h2>

<h4>打印的纸质资料要毫不留情的废弃</h4>

<h4>用电子邮件共享、保管会议资料</h4>

<p>用电子邮件管理文件的优点</p>

<ol>
<li>可以按时间顺序对邮件进行严格的管理</li>
<li>可以用发件人进行搜索</li>
<li>参考邮件内容可以回忆起当时的状况</li>
</ol>


<h4>文件按“项目名＋文件名＋创建日期”的格式来命名</h4>

<p>不仅可以项目名、文件名和制作日期来搜索文件，还能在文件夹内进行管理，按文件名重新排列文件后，所有文件就会按更新日期排列了。</p>

<p>统一日期格式</p>

<h4>用扫描仪将纸质文件变为电子文件</h4>

<p>可以很快的构建一个资料数据库，这比从资料夹中费力寻找纸质资料更有效率。</p>

<h4>整理书籍，制作电子书架</h4>

<p>me：这个现在kindle，ipad买电子书看电子书什么的很方便了，不需要再自己将纸质书扫描成电子版了。</p>

<h4>使用SugarSync实现“无障碍办公”</h4>

<p>me：就是云存储。取而代之，我有dropbox，amazon cloud drive，google drive，再加上Apple自带的iCloud。</p>

<h4>随身携带纸质资料，实现终极“无障碍办公”</h4>

<p>me：这个标题我怀疑是翻译错误。书中所说的是，在手机或随身携带的笔记本上使用云存储，这样到哪里都可以办公，实现remote，而不需要到公司。</p>

<h4>充实参考资料，随时实现工作效率最大化</h4>

<p>参考资料从某种意义上是工作智慧与经验的结晶。</p>

<p>将参考资料整理汇总，设定为多台电脑共享，就可以随时随地实现最高效的办公了。参考资料是前人智慧与经验的结晶，整理参考资料其实就是盘点前人的智慧与经验。</p>

<p><strong>参考资料是可随身携带的技能，对职业生涯的设计而言也是不可或缺的人力财富。</strong></p>

<p>我的文件夹中保存了一下文件。</p>

<ol>
<li>研讨会、演讲会资料</li>
<li>市场营销、经营企划资料</li>
<li>公司标志、产品照片、个人简介</li>
<li>安装文件。包括id、密码等</li>
</ol>


<h4>只要是文件就全部放入Magic Briefcase</h4>

<p>me：就是dropbox这类软件在本机创建的同步文件夹。</p>

<h4>在目的地或便利店打印必要的资料</h4>

<p>到外面打印东西最好将等待时间计算在内，留出充裕的时间，提前一点到便利店去。</p>

<h4>不关电脑电源，设为待机状态</h4>

<p>节约开机时间。</p>

<p><strong>要将某个程序变得更实用，就有必要一点一滴地去除操作时的“麻烦”环节。</strong></p>

<p><strong>整理术的目的就是为了“直观地把握，无须深思熟虑”或“不麻烦”，因此是一种非常具有创造性的思考方式。</strong></p>

<p>me：我用rmbp，向来是打开盖子合上盖子而已。</p>

<h4>用Google Documents、Picasa与他人共享文件</h4>

<p>实现共享文件和共同编辑文件。</p>

<p>我在Google Documents上共享的文件包括。</p>

<ol>
<li>大纲、会议记录</li>
<li>出席者名单</li>
<li>需要共享的参考资料</li>
</ol>


<h4>重要的网页可以截图</h4>

<p>me：safari直接保存为pdf</p>

<h4>分类使用SD卡，传递数据更高效</h4>

<h4>将纸质资料装入透明文件夹，按时间顺序排列</h4>

<p>纸质资料的优点之一：<strong>可视性强</strong></p>

<p><strong>对于正在进行的项目，还是应该暂时保存纸质资料，以方便办公。</strong></p>

<h4>用100日元的笔记本整理信息</h4>

<p>只用一本笔记本，所有笔记按时间顺序排列。</p>

<h4>集中数据，分散浏览场所</h4>

<h2>环境整理术——统一环境，简化环境</h2>

<h4>将小物品装入透明文件袋</h4>

<p>整理环境最重要的一个理念，是“<strong>减少杂乱感</strong>”。</p>

<h4>准备好出差用品，自由应付紧急出差</h4>

<h4>充电全靠USB解决</h4>

<h4>实现一物多用</h4>

<p>箱包的内部空间不仅可以通过减少充电器来整理，<strong>还能通过整合使用工具来整理</strong>。如iphone，带有噪音隔离功能的耳机、报事贴</p>

<h4>为笔记本电脑准备三个电源适配器</h4>

<p>一个放在公文包里随身携带,一个放在家中,一个放在办公室里。这一招不仅适用于笔记本电脑,对手机和数码相机也同样适用。总之, 对于那些电能耗尽就无法工作的工具,我们只要增加充电器,增加能充电 的地方即可。</p>

<p>me：得益于rmbp强大的电池续航能力，我只准备了两个，一个公司一个宿舍，即使出门忘了带，电池依然能提高近7小时的续航能力。萌大奶。</p>

<h4>家里和办公室使用同样的键盘和鼠标</h4>

<p>正如工匠讲究工具，具有专业精神的职场达人也应该重视自己使用的工具。职场达人绝不会毫无章法地滥用各种工具，而是精挑细选出最好的一款使用。</p>

<p>很多公司的电脑都是由公司统一配给的，很少能有诚心如意的机型。但至少我们可以统一键盘和鼠标，让公司和家里的电脑都符合自己的使用习惯，变成非常顺手的工具。</p>

<p>me：我倒没有工具使用的烦恼，我可以带自己的电脑上班。</p>

<h4>用Firefox的附加组件实现网页浏览器的个性化</h4>

<p>me：换到今天，估计要变成Chrome</p>

<h4>用Xmarks瞬间复制电脑运行环境</h4>

<p>me：额，这是个同步firefox书签的工具，我用chrome自带的。</p>

<h4>将办公桌的右半边变成激发创造力的空间</h4>

<p>将办公桌按区域划分功能。</p>

<ul>
<li>向左的视线</li>
</ul>


<p>人们在会议过去的事情时倾向于向左看。</p>

<ul>
<li>向右的视线</li>
</ul>


<p>在构想未来的蓝图时，人们更倾向于向右看。</p>

<p>右边的空间适合用于拟定未来和企划等工作。可以在那里放上计划书、必要的资料、参考书籍等。</p>

<h4>通过固定纸巾盒与笔筒的位置来保持桌面的井然有序</h4>

<h4>分隔抽屉，充分利用空间</h4>

<h4>将输入法语言栏放在电脑桌面顶端的中部</h4>

<h4>一机双屏，扩展工作领域</h4>

<p>me：废话，程序员没两个屏幕干活很不爽的。</p>

<h4>将办公桌面和电脑桌面都清理干净后再回家</h4>

<p>转化心情，收拾干净再回家。</p>

<h4>统一、简化工作环境</h4>

<p>统一环境的意愿会促使人们找出规则，开始重新审视目前为止无意间创造出来的工作环境。</p>

<h2>信息整理术——管理时间轴与空间轴</h2>

<h4>扔掉书本，提高信息吸收能力</h4>

<p>毫不犹豫地扔掉旧信息，不断吸收新信息非常重要。</p>

<p>“读罢即扔”</p>

<h4>写书评博客，制作数据库</h4>

<p>我们应该以扔书为前提，给自己制造压力，强迫自己认真阅读书中的重要部分，做好笔记。</p>

<p>等读书笔记写到一定水准，建议你开个博客，与更多的人分享信息。</p>

<h4>加原创注释，将书籍变成信息数据库</h4>

<p>不断阅读，不断记录自己的想法，一部由你和作者共同创作的新书便渐渐破茧而出。如此一来，读书就不再是被动的行为，而变成一个与作者共同创作的过程，是一个很有创造性的行为。</p>

<p>在阅读时，作为信息的接收方，你不再被动地接收信息，而成为加工信息的创造者，创造出更多新的价值。你的“信息加工能力”与“信息编辑能力”都在这种记笔记和加注释的过程中得到很好的锻炼。</p>

<h4>制作杂志文章数据库</h4>

<p>对待杂志，要遵循与书籍相同的原则，即读完就扔。</p>

<p>将自己认为值得保留的部分用扫描仪扫描成pdf即可。这些杂志文章的pdf就是珍贵的话题数据库。</p>

<h4>看报纸只记数字和关键词</h4>

<h4>用rss阅读器自动收集信息</h4>

<h4>缩印插图，制作专属于自己的词典</h4>

<p>插图是一种高浓度信息媒介，能将许多难以言表的复杂信息用视觉方式瞬间传递给读者。</p>

<p><strong>将所有信息统统塞进自制词典，就可能有空前绝后的新组合诞生。</strong></p>

<h4>将图书目录贴到笔记本上，制作图书数据库</h4>

<p>对于非常重要的书籍，无论扫描起来多麻烦也值得，仅供参考的书籍将目录复印下来就可以了，当然你也可以描述。</p>

<p>至于如何将目录贴到笔记本上，我建议不要另行制作图书专用笔记本，贴在普通的工作笔记本就可以了。如此一来，我们就能知道这本书是做哪个项目时阅读的，也能对照当时的情况，把握事情的全貌。我们肯定是对某本书的内容感兴趣或有其他缘由，才会阅读这本书的。将目录与阅读时的相关信息保存在一起，相信我们能更充分地利用书中的内容。</p>

<h4>用手机邮件和Evernote记电子笔记</h4>

<h4>在Twitter上写生活日志</h4>

<p>将网友间相互交换的实时信息原封不动地存留下来，聚沙成塔，聚石成山，就是一部名不虚传的生活纪录片。</p>

<h4>增加GPS定位功能，收集整理信息</h4>

<p>GPS定位功能也是非常重要的信息整理索引工具。</p>

<p>方位信息搜索也是信息搜索的一个重要方法。</p>

<h4>充分使用标签来整理信息</h4>

<h4>用1.5倍的放映速度看电视</h4>

<h4>用会议记录Extreme Meetings，提高会议效率</h4>

<p>不是在会议后整理会议记录，而是在开会的同时制作会议记录。</p>

<p>很重要的一点是会议记录可以呈现讨论的流程。另外，会议记录是在不断征求大家意见的同时制作的，过后就不会有“当时说的不一样”等理解和解释上的分歧了。</p>

<h4>群发邮件，使项目信息冗余化</h4>

<p>团队全体成员都清楚谁在负责什么事情，现在进展如何。万一发生紧急状况，谁都可以代替负责人继续处理。</p>

<h4>按金字塔原理写邮件</h4>

<p>要使邮件容易阅读，就要求我们的邮件尽量短小简洁，并准确传达信息，这就是金字塔原理。是一种文章写法，在开头就提出结论，接着列举多个论据来支持结论，因此文章结构是金字塔的形状，这种结构的优点是使结论一目了然。</p>

<h4>管理时间轴与空间轴</h4>

<p>将按时间轴整理过一次的信息用空间轴的管理方法再整理过一次。</p>

<h2>生活整理术——将生活常规化，再制造一些惊喜</h2>

<h4>灵活网购，简化生活</h4>

<p>me: 在今天来说，好像是废话了。</p>

<h4>购买同种商品，免去挑选烦恼</h4>

<p>这种“购买同种商品”的习惯有许多意想不到的好处</p>

<ol>
<li>使用同种产品会越用越顺手，尤其是文具。</li>
<li>存放的标准化。</li>
<li>以后不管买什么都不会茫然了。</li>
</ol>


<h4>一次大量囤积，将担忧扼杀在摇篮里</h4>

<p>囤积消耗品。</p>

<p>“不用马上去买”这种“暂时没问题”的安心感十分重要。</p>

<h4>利用便利店代收快递服务，毫无顾及地购物</h4>

<p>me：对中国来说，现在的快递送货上门，貌似对很多人来说都是不必要的。</p>

<h4>在公司收取书籍快递，提高自己的声誉</h4>

<p><strong>声誉战略</strong></p>

<h4>拒绝第二次聚会的技巧</h4>

<p>me：“第二次聚会”是日本职场特有的吧，中国没这东西。</p>

<h4>按穿着顺序整理衣服，清除早晨的烦恼</h4>

<p>me：这个顺序指的是每天穿什么衣服的顺序，即周一穿什么、周二穿什么。将穿衣模式化。想想乔布斯，貌似只有牛仔裤和高领黑毛衣。</p>

<p>让自己远离选衣服的烦恼，从而将这部分精力用在工作和学习中。</p>

<h4>建立饮食模式，进行营养管理</h4>

<p>饮食也可以模式化。</p>

<p>me：哈哈，这个貌似实习公司这边做到了，我实习的公司是没有自己饭堂的，所以中餐几个约到就出去吃，现在周一到周五都去不同的饭馆吃。学校那边，基本上在两个饭堂间轮流，下班晚了基本去个深井烧腊，再晚就去麦当劳了。</p>

<h4>打扫卫生，重振精神，提高专注力</h4>

<p>打扫卫生是整理整顿的基础。<strong>将打扫作为转变心情的契机</strong>。</p>

<p>看着周围的环境变得焕然一新，自己也会感觉小有成就吧。这种小小的成就感就像开关一样，能调动我们的积极性，使我们工作起来更精神集中，更卖力。</p>

<h4>创造家和公司以外的第三场所</h4>

<p>通过创造第三场所，扩大自己能掌握的范畴，就可以根据不同目的使用不同的场所。</p>

<h4>将生活常规化，再制造一些惊喜</h4>

<p>先让生活常规化，再加入一些惊喜作为生活的调味剂。</p>

<h2>思维整理术——分割信息与整合信息</h2>

<h4>将“不懂”的信息直接装入大脑，在无意识中进行整理</h4>

<p>在“不懂”信息的状态下，暂且让其沉睡。</p>

<h4>睡前输入，睡时工作</h4>

<p>我这样规划一天的工作：</p>

<ol>
<li>上午：以输出为中心开展工作。</li>
<li>下午：基于上午思考的结果，开展实际工作。可以做一些不需要深思熟虑也能轻松完成的工作。</li>
<li>夜晚：大脑的混沌状态在睡前达到最高峰。多花些时间将信息装入大脑。</li>
</ol>


<h4>输出信息时，尽量集中精力做一件事</h4>

<h4>提高创造力的ToDo列表制作方法</h4>

<p>关键是列出今天一定要做的事，然后从中选择工作量相对较小的输出性工作，开始一天的工作。</p>

<p>从小事做起是因为工作如同开车，冲刺时需要能量，所以要从低档起步，转动起来然后再切换到下一档。安排好工作的先后顺序，到达最高时速时才能以全部的精力开展最大的输出性工作。</p>

<h4>统筹管理ToDo列表和邮件</h4>

<p>使用Gmail的ToDo管理功能。</p>

<h4>在散步中整理思维</h4>

<p>散步时大脑会分泌化学物质，使我们冷静下来，从而比较容易整理思绪。</p>

<p>除了散步，还可以洗个热水澡或在泳池里游泳。</p>

<p>重要的是不要思考得太深，而是一带而过地想。</p>

<p><strong>越是走进死胡同，越应该放松下来放宽思绪，这样才更有机会发现新的解决方法。</strong></p>

<h4>用香精、干花等治愈系物品转换思维模式</h4>

<p>治愈系物品一般要摆放在容易让人心神不宁的地方。</p>

<h4>换一支笔，换一种思维</h4>

<h4>用图解整理思维的技巧</h4>

<ul>
<li>组合对立概念</li>
<li>将概念分解为三个要素</li>
<li>分为四象限定位  1. 能发现漏洞； 2. 可以忽略无关的事情，简单地思考问题。</li>
</ul>


<h4>用空格强行拓宽思路</h4>

<h4>用思维导图将信息网络化</h4>

<p>要将已想好的点子升格为强有力的构思，就要将其中的信息按组群这样一个信息块使用，而不是一个一个单独使用。</p>

<p>要生成“点子”的信息组群，一般需要两个流程。一是整理出尽可能多的信息，二是将整理出的信息相互联系起来（即信息网络化）。</p>

<h4>用近义词拓宽思路</h4>

<h4>给组群命名，提高一个层面来整理信息</h4>

<h4>分割信息与整合信息</h4>

<p>思维就是分割与整合信息的过程。</p>

<h2>人脉整理术——链接人脉与链接的快捷方式。</h2>

<h4>扔掉沉睡一年的名片</h4>

<p>整理名片能让你随时提高警惕，努力保持人脉的新鲜度。</p>

<h4>交换得来的名片要立刻写上交换日期</h4>

<h4>收到的名片要立刻扫描，以方便阅览</h4>

<h4>将名片读取软件当名片检索系统用</h4>

<h4>给见过面的人发送个性化的电子期刊</h4>

<h4>在突然想起时邮寄手写信件</h4>

<h4>为结识名人士举办演讲会</h4>

<h4>用Spysee掌握他人的人脉</h4>

<p>利用网络上的信息，归纳总结出与目标人物有关联和有联系的人。</p>

<h4>制作富有个性的个人名片</h4>

<h4>宣布自己愿意做的事情，回避自己不愿意做的事情</h4>

<p>自制名片时，职衔的方向性越是明确，就越能帮你回避你不愿意做的事情，也可以避免与不投缘的人接触，这样工作会变得更顺手、更愉快。</p>

<h4>给活动定主题，借此制作新闻</h4>

<h4>当中间人，向别人介绍朋友</h4>

<p>越是毫不吝惜将自己的人脉与他人共享的人，其人脉越会不断扩展。</p>

<h4>链接人脉与链接的快捷方式</h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[读《奇特的一生》]]></title>
    <link href="http://sezina.github.com/blog/2013/12/12/after-peculiar-life/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-12T14:16:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sezina.github.com/blog/2013/12/12/after-peculiar-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>第一次看到柳比歇夫这个名字是在李笑来老师的《把时间当作朋友》一书中。当时从书中看到他，我有的只是对他对时间的精确的感知感到佩服与崇拜，并没有特别在意他的时间统计法。不过倒是将书中提到的文献性小说《奇特的一生》放入了读书列表中。最近终于拜读了这本《奇特的一生》，也领略了柳比歇夫的时间统计法。</p>

<blockquote><p>“噢，路齐利，一切都不是我们的，而是别人的，只有时间是我们自己的财产，”赛纳卡写道，“造物交给我们，归我们所有的，只有这个不断流逝的、不稳定的东西。就连这个东西，谁只要愿意，都可以把它从我们手里剥夺走……人一点也不珍惜别人的时间，虽然它是唯一再怎么想也无法收回的东西。你可能会问，我对你训诲开导，我自己又是怎么做的呢？老实说，我的所作所为同那些挥霍浪费然而有条理的人一样，对自己的每一笔支出都要记账。我不能说我一点也没有浪费，但我总是心中有数，我浪费了多少，是怎么浪费的，为什么浪费的。”</p></blockquote>

<p>这段话是两千年以前写下的，那个时候的哲人就已经懂得了时间的宝贵。我们所拥有的时间是不断在减少的；不像金钱，我们没有增加我们的时间的手段，我们能够做的只是高效的利用我们的时间。身边有不少朋友抱怨自己的时间不够用，认真观察其平日里的生活，更多的是没有用好时间，没有高效的使用时间。我掩面表示我也是其中的一个。看了《奇特的一生》，让我为自己的不懂珍惜时间、没有崇敬时间感到愧疚。</p>

<p>柳比歇夫创造了时间统计法帮助他高效的利用时间在一生中取得了众多的成就。</p>

<p>在第一眼看到他的时间统计法时，我以为这个方法单纯的是为了统计时间，在上面都是死板单调的事项记录，如看了哪本书用了多长时间、写论文用了多长时间、写信用了多长时间等等，每天如此，单调而枯燥。看到后面，才发现了他的时间统计法的合理性和有效性，在单调枯燥的时间统计下，可以清楚的看到自己每天如何使用有限的时间，有多少时间是用于追求目标上。而在月度或年度总结时，能清楚的看到自己过去这段时间对时间的使用情况，然后根据过去的时间使用情况来安排接下来的工作计划，让自己的日常工作高效而稳定。</p>

<p>时间统计法的功效在于连接了过去和未来，总结过去，计划未来，充分的利用时间施展自己的才能，追逐自己的梦想。如作者在《奇特的一生》中所说：</p>

<blockquote><p>柳比歇夫在这个世界上能活多久，这是他不能决定的，可是他，作为一个人，能有充分价值地生活多少时间，却正是由他决定的。而他也做到了最充分地施展才能，最大限度地发展自己身上的人的宝贵品质，吸引着人们倾慕他。这也是他的时间统计法的结果，如果同意这样看的话；至少在一定程度上是这样。</p></blockquote>

<p>我们在这个世界上能活多久，这是我们不能决定的，可是我们，作为一个人，能有充分价值地生活多少时间，却正是由我们决定的。</p>

<p>我不禁疑问，我们能否效仿柳比歇夫使用时间统计法呢？一个能够帮助自己更有效的使用时间的方法，想必有非常多人想把它用到自己身上。真正阻碍我们使用时间统计法的，不是方法的单调枯燥，而是坚持。柳比歇夫的时间统计法使用的56年，这样的坚持是我闻所未闻的，这56年的坚持成就了他奇特的一生。在当今浮躁的社会环境下，尽管我们平日里都是锻炼有益健康，但能够坚持锻炼身体的人依然不多，更何况是一个需要长时间每天坚持才有效果的时间统计法了。因此，当前几天一个朋友拿出他的小本子向我展示他坚持实践时间统计法两个月的成果时，我惊讶不已，佩服朋友的坚持。</p>

<p>我佩服朋友的坚持，同时对自己所拥有的时间在一秒一秒的减少感到一丝不安。柳比歇夫的时间统计法是掌控自己时间的一个非常好的方法，我打算将其应用到自己身上，以获得自己时间的最大效用，成就自己奇特的一生（这目标好大啊～）。</p>

<p>不懂如何很好的使用时间和老是觉得时间不够用的人，推荐给你们这本《奇特的一生》，学习柳比歇夫是如何使用时间、如何计划工作的。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Road Less Travelled 摘录]]></title>
    <link href="http://sezina.github.com/blog/2013/12/08/the-road-less-travelled-extract/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-08T15:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sezina.github.com/blog/2013/12/08/the-road-less-travelled-extract</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/the_road_less_travelled.jpg"></p>

<p>Life if difficult.
This is a great truth, one of the greatest truths. It is a great truth because one we truly see this truth, we transcend it. Once we truly know that life is difficult — once we truly understand and accept it — then life is no longer difficult. Because once it is accepted, the fact that life is difficult no longer matters.</p>

<p>Four tools to solve problems of life:</p>

<ol>
<li>delaying of gratification</li>
<li>acceptance of responsibility</li>
<li>dedication to truth</li>
<li>balancing</li>
</ol>


<p>When we love something it is of value to us, and when something is of value to us we spend time with it, time enjoying it and time taking care of it.</p>

<p>Problems do not go away. They must be worked through or else they remain forever a barrier to the growth and development of the spirit.</p>

<p>A general, ’The single greatest problem in this army, or I guess in any organisation, is that most of the executives will sit looking at problems in their units, staring them right in the face, doing nothing, as if this problems will go away if they sit there long enough.’</p>

<p>We cannot solve life’s problems except by solving them.This is because we must accept responsibility for a problem before we can solve it.</p>

<p>The neurotic assumes too much responsibility; the person with a character disorder not enough.</p>

<p>‘If you are not part of the solution, then you are part of the problem.’</p>

<p>Transference is that set of ways of perceiving and responding to the world which is developed in childhood and which is usually entirely appropriate to the childhood environment(indeed, often life-saving) but which is inappropriately transferred into the adult environment.</p>

<p>Truth or reality is avoided when it is painful.</p>

<p>Mental health is an ongoing process of dedication to reality at all costs.</p>

<p>What does a life of total dedication to the truth mean? It is means, first of all, a life of continuous and never-ending stringent self-examination.</p>

<p>The life of wisdom must be a life of contemplation combined with action.</p>

<p>Examination of the world without is never as personally painful as examination of the world within, and it is certainly because of the pain involved in a life of genuine self-examination that the majority steer away from it.</p>

<p>A life of total dedication to the truth also  means a life of willingness to be personally challenged.</p>

<p>A black lie is a statement we make that we know is false. A white lie is a statement we make that is not in itself false but that leaves out a significant part of the truth.</p>

<p>To be free people we must assume total responsibility for ourselves, but in doing so must possess the capacity to reject responsibility that is not truly ours.</p>

<p>We therefore not only need to know how to deal with our anger in different ways at different times but also how most appropriately to match the right time with the right style of expression.</p>

<p>You must have something in order to give it up. You cannot give up anything you have not already gotten. If you give up winning without ever having won, you are where you were at the beginning: a loser.</p>

<p>Love is: The will to extend one’s self for the purpose of nurturing one’s own or another’s spiritual growth.</p>

<p>Desire is not necessarily translated into action. Will is desire of sufficient intensity that it is translated into action.</p>

<p>Falling in love is not an act of will. It is not a conscious choice.</p>

<p>Falling in love is not an extension of one’s limits or boundaries; it is a partial and temporary collapse of them. The extension of one’s limits requires effort; falling in love is effortless.</p>

<p>The misconception that falling in love is a type of love is so potent precisely because it contains a grain of truth.</p>

<p>It is impossible to really see the unity of the universe as long as one continues to see oneself as a discrete object, separate and distinguishable from the rest of the universe in any way, shape of form.</p>

<p>The temporary loss of ego boundaries involved in falling in love and sexual intercourse not only leads us to make commitments to other people from which read love may begin but also gives us a foretastes of (and therefore an incentive for) the most lasting mystical ecstasy that can be ours after a lifetime of love. As such, therefore, while falling in love is not itself love, it is a part of the great and mysterious scheme of love.</p>

<p>The second most common misconception about love is the idea that dependency in love.</p>

<p>When you require another individual for your survival, you are a parasite on that individual. There is no choice, no freedom involved in your relationship. It is a matter of necessity rather than love. Love is the free exercise of choice. Two people love each other only when they are quite capable of living without each other but choose to live with each other.</p>

<p>We all — each and every one of us — even if we try to pretend to others and to ourselves that we don’t have dependency needs and feelings. All of us have desires to be babied, to be nurtured without effort on our parts, to be cared for by persons stronger than us who have our interests truly at heart.</p>

<p>Dependency may appear to be love because it is a force that causes people to fiercely attach themselves to another. But in actuality it is not love; it is a form of antilove. It has its genesis in a parental failure to love and it perpetuates the failure. It seeks to receive rather than to give. It nourishes infantilism rather than growth. It works to trap and constrict rather than to liberate. Ultimately it destroys rather than builds relationships, and it destroys rather than builds people.</p>

<p>Dependency is but one of the forms of behaviour to which we incorrectly apply the word ‘love’ when concern for spiritual evolution is absent.</p>

<p>The only true end of love is spiritual growth or human evolution.</p>

<p>Love is not simply giving; it is judicious giving and judicious withholding as well. It is judicious praising and judicious criticizing. It is judicious arguing, struggling, confronting, urging, pushing and pulling in addition to comforting. It is leadership. The word ‘judicious’ means requiring judgement, and judgement requires more than instinct; it requires thoughtful and often painful decision-making.</p>

<p>Whenever we think of ourselves as doing something for someone else, we are in some way denying our own responsibility. Whatever we do is done because we choose to do it, and we make that choice because it is the one that satisfies us the most. Whatever we do for someone off else we do because it fulfils a need we have.</p>

<p>It is true that love involves a change in the self, but this is an extension of the self rather than a satisfice of the self.</p>

<p>In a real sense love is as selfish as nonlove. Here again there is a paradox in that love is both selfish and unselfish at the same time. It is not selfishness or unselfishness that distinguishes love from nonlove; it is them aim of the action. In the case of genuine love the aim is always spiritual growth. In the case of nonlove the aim is always something else.</p>

<p>Love is not a feeling.
The feeling of love is the emotion that accompanies the experience of cathecting. Cathecting, it will be remembered, is the process by which an object becomes important to us.</p>

<p>Genuine love is valuational rather than emotional.</p>

<p>My feelings of love may be unbound., but my capacity to be loving is limited. I therefore must choose the person on whom to focus my capacity to love , toward whom to direct my will to love. True love is not a feeling by which we are overwhelmed. It is a committed, thoughtful decision.</p>

<p>Extension of ourselves or moving out against the inertia of laziness we call work. Moving out in the face of fear we call courage. Love, then, is a form of word or a form of courage. Specifically, it is word or courage directed toward the nurture of our own or another’s spiritual growth.</p>

<p>The principal form that the work of love takes is attention.</p>

<p>True listening, total concentration on the other, is always a manifestation of love. An essential part of true listening is the discipline of bracketing, the temporary giving up or setting aside of one’s own prejudices, frames of reference and desires so as to experience as far as possible the speaker’s world from the inside, stepping inside his or her shoes.</p>

<p>Courage is not the absence of fear; it is the making of action in spite of fear, the moving out against the resistance engendered by fear into the unknown and into the future.</p>

<p>’The only real security in life lies in relishing life’s insecurity.’</p>

<p>The final and possibly the greatest risk of love is the risk of exercising power with humility.</p>

<p>‘Meekness in itself is nothing else than a true knowing and feeling of a man’s self as he is. Any man who truly sees and feels himself as he is must surely be meek indeed.’</p>

<p>Mental illness is not a product of the unconscious, it is instead a phenomenon of consciousness or a disordered relationship between the conscious and the unconscious.</p>

<p>The problem is not that human beings have such hostile and sexual feelings, but rather than human beings have a conscious mind that is so often unwilling to face these feelings and tolerate the pain of dealing with them, and that is so willing to sweep them under the rug.</p>

<p>We are almost always either less or more competent than we believe ourselves to be. The unconscious, however, knows who wee really are. A major and essential task in the process of one’s spiritual development is the conscious work of bringing one’s conscious self-concept into progressively greater congruence with reality.</p>

<p>‘I once was lost, but now am found, was blink, but now I see.’</p>

<p>The mind, which sometimes presumes to believe that there is no such thing as a miracle, is itself a miracle.</p>

<p>The process of spiritual growth is an effortful and difficult one. This is because it is conducted against a natural resistance, against a natural inclination to keep the things the way they were, to cling to the old maps and old ways of doing things, to take the easy path.</p>

<p>It is through love that we elevate ourselves. And it is through our love for others that we assist others to elevate themselves. Love, the extension of the self, is the very act of evolution. It is evolution in progress. The evolutionary force, present in all of life, manifests itself in mankind as human love. Among humanity love is the miraculous force that defies the natural law of entropy.</p>

<p>For no matter now much we may like to pussyfoot around it, all of us who postulate a loving God and really think about it eventually come to a single terrifying idea: God wants us to become Himself(or Herself of Itself). We are growing towards godhood. God is the goal of evolution. It is God who is the source of the evolutionary force and God who is the destination. This is what we mean when we say that He is the Alpha and the Omega, the beginning and the end.</p>

<p>The idea that God is actively nurturing us so that we might grow up to be like Him brings us face to face with our own laziness.</p>

<p>Each of us represent the whole human race; within each of us is the instinct for godhood and the hope for mankind, and within each of us is the original of laziness, the ever-present force of entropy pushing us back to childhood, to the womb and to the swamps from which we have evolved.</p>

<p>Our personal involvement in the fight against evil in the world is one of the ways we grow.</p>

<p>The development of consciousness is the development of awareness in our conscious mind of knowledge along with our unconscious mind, which already possesses that knowledge. It is the process of the conscious mind coming into synchrony with the unconscious.</p>

<p>We are often most in the dark when we are the most certain, and the most enlightened when we are the most confused.</p>

<p>The path of spiritual growth is a path of lifelong learning.</p>

<p>Spiritual power is not simply awareness; it is the capacity to maintain one’s ability to still make decisions with greater and greater awareness. And godlike power is the power to make decisions with total awareness.</p>

<p>Those who have faced their mental illness, accepted total responsibility for it, and made the necessary changes in themselves to overcome it, find themselves not only cured and free from the curses of their childhood and ancestry but also find themselves living in a new and different world. What they once perceived as problems they now perceive as opportunities. What were once loathsome barriers are now welcome challenge. Thoughts previously unwanted become helpful insights; feelings previously disowned become sources of energy and guidance. Occurrences that once seemed to be burdens now seem to be gifts, including the very symptoms from which they have recovered.</p>

<p>Christ’s assertion ‘Many are called, but few are chosen’ I would translate to mean ‘All of us are called by and to grace, but few of us choose to listen to the call.’</p>

<p>To be aware of grace, to personally experience its constant presence, to know one’s nearness to God, is to know and continually experience an inner tranquillity and peace that few possess. On the other hand, the knowledge and awareness brings with it an enormous responsibility. For to experience one’s closeness to God is also to experience the obligation to be God, to be the agent of His power and love. The call to grace is a call to a life of effortful caring, to a life of service and whatever sacrifice seems required. It is a call out of spiritual childhood into adulthood, a call to be a parent unto mankind.</p>

<p>Saint Augustine wrote, ‘Dilige et quod vis fac,’ meaning ‘If you are loving and diligent, you may do whatever you want.’</p>

<p>The awareness of the existence of grace can be of considerable assistance to those who have chosen to travel the difficult path of spiritual growth. For this awareness will facilitate their journey in at least three ways: it will help them to take advantage of grace along the way; it will give them a surer sense of direction; and it will provide encouragement.</p>

<p>For the journey of spiritual growth requires courage and initiative and independence of thought and action. While the words of the prophets and the assistance of grace are available, the journey must be traveled alone. No teacher can carry you there. There are no preset formulas. Rituals are only learning aids, they are not the learning.</p>

<p>No words can be said, no teaching can be taught that will relieve spiritual travellers from the necessity of picking their own ways, working out with effort and anxiety their own paths through the unique circumstances of their own lives toward the identification of their individual selves with God.</p>

<p>Through grace we are helped not to stumble and through grace we know that we are being welcomed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
